Masoud Haghbin | Software Engineer

☐ masoud.haghbin7@gmail.com

in Masoud Haghbin

+989022022411

ABOUT

Software Engineer with more than 7 years of experience. Led a team of software engineers to design and develop cloud-native microservices with Golang and PHP using Agile methodologies like Scrum. Engaged in Ops: CICD, Docker, Kubernetes, Openshift and experienced in software approaches like TDD, and DDD.

EXPERIENCE

Snapp! Tehran, Iran

Technical Team Lead

May 2022 - Now

- o Snapp is the first and leading mobile and web-based ride-hailing platform like Uber in Iran. Snapp is currently on the verge of scaling and has more than 4 million rides each day
- o As head of a cross-functional team, I collaborated in Business Vision (OKRs) Meetings to design technical solutions to achieve market share stability, profitability, etc.
- o Engaged in system architecture designs for delivering complex product features like demand queue to optimize the offering mechanism which increased 4% in ride's fulfillment rate and acceptance Rate
- o Engaged in Hiring, Performance management and, 101 meetings

Senior Software Engineer

March 2022 - May 2022

- o Engaged in complete Software Development Life Cycle including System Requirements Collection, Architecture, Design, Coding, Development, Testing. Maintenance and Enhancement in a variety of technological platforms.
- o Contributed in developing new deployment pipelines to migrate team microservices into cloud infrastructure
- o Contributed to the migration to microservices in Golang by dividing the legacy PHP monolith into several bounded contexts and implementing communication between them with events, messaging, gRPC and REST API calls

Software Engineer

July 2019 - March 2022

- o Implementing major features in the offering system such as broadcasting, multi-casting, dynamic radius, in-ride allotment, and caching to match drivers and rides efficiently in a system with more that 40M daily ride offers.
- o Implementation of the live driver locations services for processing and storing more than 50K locations per second through Message Broker (EMQ) and REST API as well as providing services for geo-searching over the locations

Sportiv

Telecommute Toronto, Canada

Software Engineer

December 2018 - July 2019

- o Sportiv is a Canadean start-up that helps you to play more of the sports you love.
- o As the head of the Backend team in Sportiv, Our team and I developed and deployed APIs for business.
- o Technologies used: PHP, Laravel, MySQL, Redis, Gitlab CI/CD, Sentry, Firebase, Pubnub Messaging

Andishe Computer Co

Tehran, Iran

Tehran, Iran

Software Engineer

December 2017 - November 2018

- o Developing the new version of Web-based Electricity Billing Application which is used by 6-7 Power Distribution Companies that handle the data of over 10M Power subscribers from all over the country
- o Technologies used: PHP, Laravel, Redis, MongoDB, Node.js, SQLServer

Narnia Online Store

Co-Founder & Full-Stack Software Engineer

March 2017 - December 2017

o Developed and Deployed www.narnia.ir Website Front-End and Back-End

- o Technologies used: PHP, Laravel, Redis, MySQL, CSS, jQuery, Elastic

Behpardaz Pishro Co

Backend Software Engineer

August 2016 - February 2017

o Developed a web-based software Gathering information of about 32M subscribers of Electricity from all over the country, Generating reports on any aspect of the data, e.g. Sales, Receipts, Branch Infos, etc

- o Automatic Calculation of almost 100K Bills and fetch related data from Banking services for over 2K customers.
- o Technologies used: PHP, Laravel, MongoDB, Oracle, Bootstrap, ¡Query

SociaSoft Co Tehran, Iran

Software Engineer

May 2015 - July 2016

Tehran, Iran

- Developed and Deployed Tooshe Web Application
- o Tooshe is a collaborative community that connects travelers with people with shipping needs (like sending or buying Products from all around the world.) in order to decrease shipping fees
- o Technologies used: PHP, Laravel, MySQL, HTML, CSS, jQuery

SKILLS

- Strong knowledge of Golang
- o Strong technical skills, knowledge in PHP programming language and Laravel, Lumen Framework
- Very good knowledge of relevant technologies, such as Redis, Caching, Git, CI/CD, Testing, Docker, Openshift, Kubernetes, Nginx, Cloud Messaging, Monitoring, Grafana, Prometheus, MariaDb, EMQ, Load testing, Message Brokers like RabbitMQ, Ansible, Tracing and Profiling, Helm, Swagger, MongoDB, MySQL, SQL Server, REST, gRPC, Protobuf
- o Good Knowledge of Design Patterns, OOP, MVC, CRUD, SOLID
- o Good Knowledge of Linux and familiar with bash scripting
- o Familiar with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery
- Good Knowledge of Computer Networks, Network and Socket Programming, Wireless Networking and new Network paradigms like SDN
- Excellent English communication skills
- Rapid Learner and eager to learn new technologies

EDUCATION

University of Passau

Exchange Student of Information Technology

Amirkabir University of Technology

Master of Information Technology in Computer Networks engineering

Iran University of Science and Technology

Bachelor of Technology in Computer engineering

Passau, Germany

September 2017 - March 2018

Tehran, Iran

September 2016 - May 2019

Tehran, Iran

September 2012 - September 2016

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Certificate of Fluency in English
- o A1 Deutsch Degree from University of Passau
- CCNA and Network+ Degree with Score of 100